http://www.lsoft.com/corporate/privacypolicy.asp

L-Soft Privacy Policy
At L-Soft, we are committed to the protection of your privacy and personal data. As a subscriber of our email lists, visitor to our website, or customer of our products and services, you decide what information to give us. Any information that you provide will be held securely and in accordance with the legal regulations of data protection and electronic communication.
In accordance with our corporate policy, L-Soft pledges that it will never release, sell or trade your personal information without your consent. An exception must be made if we are required to do so by law or in the unlikely event of a sale of the business or transfer of assets.
The information that we gather falls into two categories:
Personally Identifiable Information: Personally identifiable information is any kind of information about a specific user, including name, email address and company. L-Soft only collects personally identifiable information that you explicitly give us.
Non-Personally Identifiable Information: Non-personally identifiable information is any type of information collected in web logs, including IP address, browser type, or the use of cookies. This information is only viewed in aggregate form and is not routinely tracked to an individual site visitor except in special cases, such as responding to Internet-based attacks.
Our privacy policies provide important disclosures and details regarding our usage of your information.
Privacy Policy for Email Lists
L-Soft has always been a strong advocate of permission-based email list communication. Our email list management software LISTSERV® has supported the opt-in function since 1986. In 1993, LISTSERV became the first software to introduce double opt-in, now an industry standard for email list subscriptions, which requires subscribers to respond to an email confirmation before being subscribed to a list. LISTSERV was also the first software in the industry with a spam filter and built-in virus protection. Our products are designed to put users in control of their own personal information.
Note that this privacy policy only applies to L-Soft's corporate email lists. While we urge all LISTSERV customers to follow the best practices of email communication, L-Soft is not responsible for customers' privacy policies. It is up to the discretion of individual licensees of the software to determine what information they collect and how they process and store it.
L-Soft collects personally identifiable information to serve email list subscribers in the most effective and efficient manner possible:
Opt-In: If you sign up to receive L-Soft email announcements or newsletters, we will use the information that you give us to provide the service that you have requested. The personal information that you provide will only be held for as long as you remain subscribed to the email lists. L-Soft issues subscriptions and collects your personally identifiable information according to a double opt-in policy.
Opt-Out: All of L-Soft's corporate announcement list messages include an unsubscribe option at the end of the message. If you inform us that you wish to cancel a subscription, we will promptly remove you from our mailing list, and your personal details will be deleted from our records.
Information Collected: Information collected may include your full name, email address, country and other information depending on your preference for a specific service. L-Soft communications are in plain text or HTML format (with images). When you sign up to receive email from us, you can select either of them. If you select the HTML format, the email may include a one-pixel gif to determine whether or not readers viewed the email. This process does not leave any information on your computer.
L-Soft complies fully with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003, EU Directive 2002/58/CE on Privacy and Electronic Communications, and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). For more detailed information on data protection regulations, please see the legal framework section.
L-Soft keeps your data accurate to the extent that you provide us with the information needed to do so. If your data changes (e.g. new email address), then you are responsible for notifying us. Upon request, L-Soft will provide customers with information about whether we store, or process on behalf of a third party, any of their personal data. L-Soft may use personal data to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent abuse and enforce agreements.
Privacy Policy for Website
As is standard practice on many websites, L-Soft logs non-personally identifiable information about site visitors to analyze website traffic. This information is not routinely tracked to individual site visitors. It is only viewed and analyzed in aggregate form except in special cases, such as responding to Internet-based attacks.
IP Address: An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a TCP/IP network. L-Soft logs IP addresses to analyze traffic and improve the content of the website. L-Soft does not routinely track IP addresses to individual users. In special cases, such as responding to Internet-based attacks or troubleshooting customer or subscriber problems, logs for web and other Internet services may be used to track the particular IP addresses that are involved in the incident.
Cookie: A cookie is a message given to a web browser by a web server. The message is sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. The main purpose of cookies is to identify users, and, in some cases, to prepare customized web pages for them. The L-Soft website uses cookies to remember user regional preferences. L-Soft also uses cookies on a permission basis by offering LISTSERV administrators, list owners and subscribers the possibility to store their passwords with the help of a cookie. L-Soft does not use cookies to track individual users.
Web Forms: Web forms are used on the L-Soft website as a mechanism for site visitors to contact L-Soft. The web forms collect information, including name, email address and company name. This information is only used to answer and follow up on the request and is not shared with any third party unless explicitly mentioned.
Privacy Policy for Other Electronic Communication
Purchases: If you purchase an L-Soft product or service, L-Soft will require you to provide appropriate data to fulfill the legal requirements on commercial transactions.
Inquiries and Support: If you send an inquiry or support request by email to a specific contact at L-Soft, it may not always be possible for this contact to provide the information requested. In such circumstances, we may pass your inquiry to another recipient who can fulfill your information request.
L-Soft Privacy Policy for EU Residents' Personal Data
1. Scope
L-Soft's privacy policy for EU residents' personal data applies to the processing of EU personal data that L-Soft receives from its hosting (ListPlex, EASE) customers, regardless of the location of the L-Soft data center where the information is stored. Most L-Soft customers are businesses, not individuals. However, L-Soft may also receive personal data about EU individuals from its hosting customers. We process this personal data only on behalf of and under the direction of the customer. The collection, use and disclosure of such data is subject to the customer's own privacy policy.
L-Soft's privacy policy for EU residents' personal data does not cover data through which individuals are no longer identifiable.
2. Processing of Personal Data
L-Soft may collect personal data directly or indirectly from customers or from L-Soft affiliates. L-Soft also collects information while conducting our business operations or in furtherance of our legitimate business interests that could lead to the incidental collection of personal data. L-Soft uses personal data for legitimate business purposes, including to:
Process orders
Prepare invoices and complete billing tasks
Prepare price quotations
Provide services to customers, including the delivery of email messages or other communications to a customer's email subscribers
Provide technical support or consulting services
Respond to customer inquiries about their L-Soft products and services
Satisfy governmental reporting and tax requirements
Satisfy security, health, and safety concerns
Satisfy other business-related purposes required under applicable laws and regulations
3. Data Security
L-Soft uses reasonable efforts to maintain the integrity of personal data. L-Soft also uses reasonable safeguards designed to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of data that we maintain. All electronically stored personal data are kept on a secure storage system that cannot be accessed from the Internet (DAS or SAN). In the unlikely event of a data breach of personal data, L-Soft will analyze the impact and notify the affected customers without undue delay.
4. Personal Data Rights
EU individuals have a right to access, change or delete their personal data. The most expedient method is to contact the data controller directly. Upon reasonable request and to the extent the request does not compromise the protections set forth in this Policy, L-Soft will facilitate a response by forwarding a GDPR-related request to the pertinent customer (controller). If you have a request concerning your personal data held by L-Soft as a processor of such data, please contact us at:http://www.lsoft.com/econtact.asp?id=gdpr
For more information about GDPR, visit:http://www.lsoft.com/resources/gdpr.asphttp://www.lsoft.com/resources/gdpr-faq.asp
Contacting L-Soft
L-Soft welcomes your comments regarding these privacy statements. If you would like to know what L-Soft email lists you are subscribed to or to submit questions or comments, feel free to contact us at: editor@lsoft.com. Your feedback will help us improve our service to our customers.
To reflect this feedback, we may occasionally amend this privacy policy; thus, we encourage you to periodically review this page for any updates on our commitment to protect your information and provide you with improved content on our website.
LISTSERV is a registered trademark licensed to L-Soft international, Inc.
See Guidelines for Proper Usage of the LISTSERV Trademark for more details.
All other trademarks, both marked and unmarked, are the property of their respective owners.
ManagementStory of L-SoftStory of LISTSERVJobs at L-SoftLISTSERV TrademarkTrademark UsagePrivacy Policy
Resource Center
Technical SupportManualsRenewalsSoftware Tune-UpTech TipsWhite PapersLearn LISTSERV
News Center
Subscription CenterNewsletterUser ForumsRSS FeedsSocial MediaPress ReleasesBlog
Contact L-Soft
SalesTechnical SupportTrainingConsultingPublic RelationsHuman ResourcesWebmaster
Sign Up to L-Soft's Newsletter
Keep learning about LISTSERV:
See Newsletter Archives
